Guide to the Elsie H. Hillman Papers, 1920-2015 AIS.2013.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Community Involvement, 1946-2013; IV.
  - Hillman Cancer Center (Shadyside Hospital and UPCI), 1946-2012; 14.
    Subseries 14 contains correspondence, memoranda, articles, newspaper clippings, press releases, and other records covering Elsie Hillman's involvement in the planning and establishment of the Hillman Cancer Center in addition to her prior involvement with Shadyside Hospital and the University of Pittsburgh Cancer Institute (UPCI). Hillman served on the board of Shadyside Hospital up until the acquisition of Shadyside Hospital by UPMC in 1996. Hillman was also involved with the University of Pittsburgh Cancer Institute, a regional cancer care and research consortium. Her involvement with UPMC increased further with the establishment of the Hillman Cancer Center, the flagship center for the UPCI. The center, located in Shadyside, began construction in 1999 and was opened in 2002. As a result, there are a number of files relating to the planning of the opening ceremonies and events associated with the Hillman Cancer Center.
    - Building a Future Without Cancer Event, 2005 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1986-2012 (Box 68, Folder 2-4)
    - Highmark Negotiations, 2002 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Hillman Cancer Center, Bioterrorism Preparedness Appropriations Request, 2003 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Hillman Cancer Center, Case Statement for State Funding, 1999 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Hillman Cancer Center, Congratulatory Correspondence on Opening, 2002 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Hillman Cancer Center, Consultation of Design of Placement of Artwork and Sculpture, 2001 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Hillman Cancer Center, Correspondence, 2001-2005 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Hillman Cancer Center, Donor and Contributions List, 2001 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Hillman Cancer Center, Groundbreaking Event Invitation, 1999 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Hillman Cancer Center, Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1999-2013 (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Hillman Cancer Center, Opening Events Agenda and Schedules, 2002 (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Hillman Cancer Center, Program Booklets for Hospital Events, 2004-2010 (Box 68, Folder 15-16)
    - News Bureau Fact Sheets, c.2005 (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Pittsburgh Cancer Institute, Missions and Goals, c.1980s (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Pittsburgh Cancer Institute, Reception Guest List, 1990 (Box 68, Folder 19)
    - Pittsburgh Cancer Institute, Regional Advisory Council Meeting Minutes, 1992 (Box 68, Folder 20)
    - Pittsburgh Cancer Institute, State Legislator Fundraising Trip, 1990 (Box 68, Folder 21)
    - Shadyside Hospital, Correspondence, 1963-1996 (Box 68, Folder 22)
    - Shadyside Hospital, Pittsburgh Symphony Benefit Concert, Newspaper Clipping, 1946 (Box 68, Folder 23)
    - Spirit of Hope Gala, List of Guests and Sponsors, 1998 (Box 68, Folder 24)
    - University of Pittsburgh Cancer Institute Council and Leadership Retreat, Report, 1996 (Box 68, Folder 25)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1959-2013; 15.
    Subseries 15 contains correspondence, mailings, lecture notes, and other records covering Elsie Hillman's involvement with the University of Pittsburgh. Subseries 15 is broken up into two sections; the Institute of Politics, and Other University Interactions.
    Hillman, a prominent political figure in the region, had been involved for many years in the activities of the University of Pittsburgh's Institute of Politics, participating in seminars on civic and political engagement. In 2009, the Institute conducted a case study on the political life of Hillman, culminating with the release of Never a Spectator: The Political Life of Elsie Hillman by Kathy McCauley. The case study was released in May 2012, in conjunction with an event held at Carnegie Music hall, which paid tribute to Hillman's political career and included a discussion of the study itself. (Never a Spectator, 1)
    Additionally, Hillman was involved in numerous other University activities. These include support for the Hillman library, named for her father-in-law, John Hartwell Hillman, and numerous guest lectures, speeches, and addresses.
    - Institute of Politics
      - Changing the Face of Pennsylvania Politics Seminar, Correspondence, 1994 (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - "Elections and the Electorate Today" Seminar, 1995 (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - Mailed Reports and Booklets, 1991-1992 (Box 69, Folder 4)
      - Mailing Packet, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 5)
      - Memoranda and Meeting Minutes, 1992 (Box 69, Folder 6)
      - Never A Spectator: The Political Life of Elsie Hillman, Book by Kathy McCauley, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 7)
      - Never a Spectator, Correspondence, 2003-2012 (Box 69, Folder 8)
      - Never a Spectator, Final Draft, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 9)
      - Never a Spectator, Interviews and Story Requests, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 10)
      - Never a Spectator, Photo Collection and Archival Materials Used in Case Study, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 11)
      - Never a Spectator, Poem composed after completion of Case Study, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 12)
      - Never a Spectator, Proposed Outline, c.2010 (Box 69, Folder 13)
      - Never a Spectator Event, Congratulatory Correspondence, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 14-16)
      - Never a Spectator Event, Institute of Politics Report Covering the Event, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 17)
      - Never a Spectator Event, Master Guest List, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 18)
      - Never a Spectator Event, Newspaper Articles, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 19)
      - Never a Spectator Event, Planning Materials and Discussion Panel Questions, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 20)
      - Never a Spectator Event, Proclamation Honoring Hillman from Allegheny County Council, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 21)
      - Never a Spectator Event, Program, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 22)
      - Never a Spectator Event, Remarks by Chancellor Mark Nordenberg, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 23)
      - Never a Spectator Event, Thank You Card to Attendees, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 24)
      - Nomination of Helen Faison for Coleman Award, 2011 (Box 69, Folder 25)
      - "Once Upon a Time in Pittsburgh," Scrapbook, 2014 (Box 69, Folder 26)
      - Women in Politics Advisory Committee, 1992 (Box 69, Folder 27)
    - Other University Interactions
      - American Experience Seminars, 1988-1994 (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - Archives of Industrial Society Oral History Interview, Thank You Note and Interview Transcript, 1999 (Box 70, Folder 2)
      - Dick Thornburgh Archival Collection, Thank You letter, 1999 (Box 70, Folder 3)
      - Graduate School of Public Health, 1973 (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Guest Lecture, Women in Politics, 1984 (Box 70, Folder 5)
      - History of Gender Relations Seminar, 1991 (Box 70, Folder 6)
      - K. Leroy Irvis Archives and Reading Room Dedication, Program and Remarks, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 7)
      - Luncheon with Nikita Khrushchev, Invitation and Newspaper Clipping, 1959 (Box 70, Folder 8)
      - Pitt Libraries Campaign, 1974 (Box 70, Folder 9)
      - School of Medicine, Board of Visitors, 1974-1979 (Box 70, Folder 10)
      - University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, Commencement Address and Related Materials, 1993 (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Urban League of Pittsburgh, 1971-1998; 16.
    Subseries 16 contains correspondence, memoranda, reports, and other records related to Elsie Hillman's involvement in the Urban League of Pittsburgh. The Urban League is a community based organization, working to provide services to the African American community. A member, and one time Vice-President, Hillman worked with other members of the Pittsburgh chapter to help provide services to the larger African-American community. In addition to records relating to the Pittsburgh chapter, there are a number of files relating to various personnel at either the local or national level of the Urban League.
    - Black Labor Union Committee Demands to Western Electric (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Board of Director's Lists, 1971-1974 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Certificate of Membership to President's Club, 1984 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1996 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - Jordan, Vernon, 1972-1973 (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - Memorandum, 1973 (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - Report on Sickle-Cell Activities, 1974 (Box 70, Folder 18)
    - Ronald H. Brown Leadership Banquet, Program, 1998 (Box 70, Folder 19)
    - Young, Whitney, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 20)
  - Victor Borge, 1948-2009; 17.
    Subseries 17 contains correspondence, newspaper clippings, concert programs and other records covering Elsie Hillman's friendship with Victor Borge, a Danish Classical Pianist and Comedian. Hillman and Borge first met when he played for the Pittsburgh Symphony Orchestra in 1948. They remained friends until his death in 2000. As a result of their friendship there is a significant amount of and correspondence, including a letter from a family member of Borge years after his death.
    - Booklets profiling Victor Borge, c.1970s-1990s (Box 70, Folder 21)
    - Concert Programs, 1948, 2000 (Box 70, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1953-2006 (Box 70, Folder 23)
    - Memorial Tribute to Victor Borge, Concert Program, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 24)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1948-2000 (Box 70, Folder 25)
    - Scandinavian Review, Profile on Borge, "Fiveever Two of a Kind", 2009 (Box 70, Folder 26)
  - WQED, 1972-2004; 18.
    Subseries 18 contains correspondence, newspaper clippings, event programs, and other records covering Elsie Hillman's involvement with WQED Media. A one-time volunteer, and later Board Chair of WQED, Elsie Hillman was involved in various WQED Events, including the WQED TV Auctions. Hillman would later be honored in 1996 with a tribute event called "For the Love of Elsie" which later laid the foundation for the Elsie Awards, a biennial award show named after Hillman herself. In addition to records relating to WQED Broadcasts and Events, there are a number of files covering the White House Exhibition held at Kaufmann's Department Store in 1989.
    - 1972 WQED Great TV Auction, Correspondence and Newsletter (Box 70, Folder 27)
    - 1973 WQED Great TV Auction, Congratulatory Correspondence (Box 70, Folder 28)
    - 1973 WQED Great TV Auction, Correspondence (Box 70, Folder 29)
    - 1973 WQED Great TV Auction, Newsletter and Newspaper Clippings (Box 70, Folder 30)
    - 1973 WQED Great TV Auction, Progress Report and Memoranda (Box 70, Folder 31)
    - 1974 WQED Great TV Auction, Correspondence (Box 70, Folder 32)
    - 1975 WQED Great TB Auction, Newsletter (Box 70, Folder 33)
    - 1976 WQED Great TV Auction, Correspondence (Box 70, Folder 34)
    - 1976 WQED Great TV Auction, Newsletter and Newspaper Clippings (Box 70, Folder 35)
    - 1976 WQED Great TV Auction, Newspaper Clipping of Paul Newman with Signed Toilet (Box 70, Folder 36)
    - 1977 WQED Great TV Auction, Donor Forms (Box 70, Folder 37)
    - 1998 Elsie Awards, Event Schedule and Biographies on Award Recipients (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - 1998 Elsie Awards, Newspaper Clippings (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - 1998 Elsie Awards, Program (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - 2000 Elsie Awards, Invitation (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - 2000 Elsie Awards, Newspaper Clippings (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - 2000 Elsie Awards, Script (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - 2000 Elsie Awards, Speech Introducing Michael Keaton (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - 2000 Elsie Awards, Thank you letter from Michael Keaton (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - 2002 Elsie Awards, Correspondence (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - 2002 Elsie Awards, Invitation (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - 2002 Elsie Awards, Newspaper Clippings (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - 2002 Elsie Awards, Poem Composed by Hillman (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - 2002 Elsie Awards, Program Booklet (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - 2002 Elsie Awards, Proposed Schedule for Barbara Bush (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - 2002 Elsie Awards, Sponsorship Information, 2002 (Box 71, Folder 15)
    - 2004 Elsie Awards, Invitation and Partial Guest List (Box 71, Folder 16)
    - 2004 Elsie Awards, Newspaper Clippings and Articles (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - 2004 Elsie Awards, Partial Biographies of Honorees (Box 71, Folder 18)
    - 2004 Elsie Awards, Postcard, 2003 (Box 71, Folder 19)
    - 2004 Elsie Awards, Program Booklet (Box 71, Folder 20)
    - 2004 Elsie Awards, Script (Box 71, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1973-2002 (Box 71, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, Contribution made to WQED, 2003 (Box 71, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, Letters concerning Retirement from WQED Board, 1995 (Box 71, Folder 24)
    - "For the Love of Elsie" Event, Congratulatory Correspondence, 1996 (Box 71, Folder 25)
    - "For the Love of Elsie" Event, Invitation, 1996 (Box 71, Folder 26)
    - "For the Love of Elsie" Event, Newspaper Clippings, 1996 (Box 71, Folder 27)
    - "For the Love of Elsie" Event, Poem read by Hillman, 1996 (Box 71, Folder 28)
    - "For the Love of Elsie" Event, Program, 1996 (Box 71, Folder 29)
    - Fred Rogers, Andre Watts Concert in Honor of Fred Rogers, 2004 (Box 71, Folder 30)
    - Fred Rogers, Reflection on Memory of Fred Rogers in Pittsburgh Magazine, 2003 (Box 71, Folder 31)
    - Gulf-National Geographic Screening, 1981 (Box 71, Folder 32)
    - National Geographic Television Specials, 1974-1975 (Box 71, Folder 33)
    - Newspaper Clipping, "Chairman's TV Auction", c. 1970s (Box 71, Folder 34)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1994-1995 (Box 71, Folder 35)
    - Public Broadcasting Service, 1991 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - "The Big Picture: A Show about Allegheny County", 1991 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - White House Exhibition, Budget, 1989-1990 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - White House Exhibition, Committee and Staff Lists, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - White House Exhibition, Fact Sheet and Ticket Information, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - White House Exhibition, Invitation and Program Materials, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - White House Exhibition, Memoranda, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - White House Exhibition, Planning Meeting Materials, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - White House Exhibition, Press and Message from the President, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - White House Exhibition, Preview Party Agenda and RSVP List, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - White House Exhibition, Report to the Board of Directors, 1990 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - White House Exhibition, Thank you letter from WQED Staff, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - White House Exhibition, Thank you letters sent by Lloyd Kaiser, 1990 (Box 72, Folder 13)
  - Various Arts and Cultural Activity, 1963-2009; 19.
    Subseries 19 contains correspondence, newspaper clippings, and other records covering Elsie Hillman's interest and support in various art and cultural activities. A long-time supporter of the arts and cultural activities, Hillman has supported numerous institutions including Westminster Choir College, and the Carnegie Museums of Pittsburgh.
    - African American Music Tree, 2007 (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Carnegie Museums of Pittsburgh, 1996-2002 (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - DiCarlow, David, 2001 (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Marshall, Rob, Conceptual Images of Memoirs of a Geisha, c. 2004 (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - Shadyside Academy, Hillman Center for Performing Arts, 2003-2005 (Box 72, Folder 18)
    - Southern Alleghenies Museum of Art, 1993 (Box 72, Folder 19)
    - Teenie Harris Documentary, Letters of Support, 2003 (Box 72, Folder 20)
    - Three Rivers Art Festival, 1963 (Box 72, Folder 21)
    - "Up-Home" Documentary, Signed Screening Invitation, 1975 (Box 72, Folder 21)
    - Western Pennsylvania Conservancy's Fallingwater, Fallingwater Cookbook Party, Newspaper Clippings, 2008 (Box 72, Folder 22)
    - Western Pennsylvania Conservancy's Fallingwater, Fallingwater Cookbook Party, Photo featured in Fanfare Magazine, 2009 (Box 72, Folder 23)
    - Westminster Choir College, Endowment Campaign, 2001-2008 (Box 72, Folder 24)
    - Westmoreland Museum of American Art, Fiftieth Anniversary Ball, Newspaper Clipping, 2009 (Box 72, Folder 25)
- Speeches and Writings, 1973-2013; V.
  Series V contains speech notes, transcripts, remarks, editorials, op-eds, and press statements by Elsie Hillman. The folders in this series are general arranged chronologically.
  - Syria Mosque, On Political Background, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - United Jewish Federation, Interfaith Roll Call, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - American Association of University Women, 1973 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Pennsylvania Women's Political Caucus of Allegheny County, 1973 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Ross Township, 1975 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Duquesne University, Possible Commencement Speech, c.1970s (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Pittsburgh Magazine, "The Pittsburgh I love," by Elsie Hillman, 1980-1981 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Equal Rights Amendment Rally, "ERA cannot die!", 1981 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Rolling Rock Club, "Politics Today", 1982 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - Community College of Allegheny County, "Women on Boards", 1983 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - Pittsburgh Vectors, On Allegheny Conference, 1983 (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - Women in the Urban Crisis, 1983 (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - Beth Shalom, "Pioneer Women", 1984 (Box 73, Folder 13)
  - Calvary Episcopal Church, "Men of Calvary", 1984 (Box 73, Folder 14)
  - Carlow College, Women and Politics, 1984 (Box 73, Folder 15)
  - Ellis School, Commencement Address, 1984 (Box 73, Folder 16)
  - "Pioneer Women and Women's Issues", 1984 (Box 73, Folder 17)
  - Pittsburgh Chamber of Commerce, On the Presidential Election, 1984 (Box 73, Folder 18)
  - Mount Lebanon Council of Republican Women, 1985 (Box 73, Folder 19)
  - Bradford County, c. 1986 (Box 73, Folder 20)
  - Pike County, c. 1986 (Box 73, Folder 21)
  - Penn Hills Council of Republican Women, 1987 (Box 73, Folder 22)
  - Pennsylvania Council of Republican Women, Current State of the Republican Party, c. 1987 (Box 73, Folder 23)
  - Bush, George H.W., Speech Introducing Vice-President Bush, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 24)
  - Bush, George, H.W., Speech Notes on Presidential Qualities, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 25)
  - Heinz, H. John III, Nominating Remarks by Hillman, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 26)
  - Marywood College, Seminar for Teachers, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 27)
  - Remarks made as President of the State Electoral College, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 28)
  - Burns, Billy, "Ode to Billy Burns", 1989 (Box 73, Folder 29)
  - Ellis School, Commencement Address, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 30)
  - Ellis School, On President-Elect Bush, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 31)
  - Executive Women's Conference, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 32)
  - Pittsburgh Blind Association, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 33)
  - Republican National Committee, Seconding Nomination Speech for Lee Atwater, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 34)
  - Women's Press Club, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 35)
  - Fayette County Republican Dinner, c. 1989 (Box 73, Folder 36)
  - Volunteerism, Notes, c. 1989 (Box 73, Folder 37)
  - "Role of Chairmen - Local and County Organization," Notes, c. 1970s-1980s (Box 73, Folder 38)
  - Bush, George H.W., Speech Notes, c. 1980s (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Local Political Participation, Notes, c. 1980s (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Pennsylvania Council of Republican Women, Women in Politics, c. 1980s (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Political Involvement, Notes, c. 1980s (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Right Wing Politics, Notes, c. 1980s (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Shadyside Presbyterian Church, "Women in Politics", c. 1980s (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Valley Forge, c. 1980s (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Women Business Owners, c. 1980s (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Mellon University, "What is Expected of You?", 1990, 2007 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Point Park University, Commencement Address, 1990 (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Rotary Club of Pittsburgh, 1990 (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - "Thoughts on Leadership," Notes, 1990 (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - Pi Lambda Theta Delta Chapter, 1991 (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - Allegheny County Country Club, 1992 (Box 74, Folder 14)
  - Allegheny County Medical Association Women's Auxiliary, 1992 (Box 74, Folder 15)
  - City Lights, "City Leaders discuss Pittsburgh's Renaissance," Contribution by Elsie Hillman, 1992 (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - Veteran's Day, 1992 (Box 74, Folder 17)
  - "Women in Politics - Directions and Decisions", 1992 (Box 74, Folder 18)
  - "Current Topics in Politics", c. 1992 (Box 74, Folder 19)
  - Republican National Committee, Seconding Nomination Speech for Haley Barbour, 1993 (Box 74, Folder 20)
  - Republican State Committee, 1993 (Box 74, Folder 21)
  - Rodef Shalom, Hadassah Myrtle Wreath Award Remarks, 1993 (Box 74, Folder 22)
  - United Way Heart of the Community Dinner, Honoring the Steelers, 1998 (Box 74, Folder 23)
  - Pittsburgh Conference of Jewish Women's Organizations Annual Meeting, 1998-1999 (Box 74, Folder 24)
  - Twentieth Century Club, 1999 (Box 74, Folder 25)
  - United Jewish Federation, "Building Community Through Philanthropy", 1999 (Box 74, Folder 26)
  - Republican National Committee, Speech in Support of RNC Chairman Haley Barbour, c.1990s (Box 74, Folder 27)
  - United Jewish Federation Youth Division, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 28)
  - Speech to Students on Political and Civic Engagement, c. 2000 (Box 74, Folder 29)
  - Epperson, David, Dinner Speech, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 30)
  - Federation of Independent Schools Foundation, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 31)
  - Grantmakers of Western Pennsylvania, "Family Philanthropy: Making a Difference in the Community and Your Family", 2001 (Box 74, Folder 32)
  - League of Women Voters, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 33)
  - Rotary Club of Pittsburgh, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 34)
  - Mount Ararat Community Activity Center, Honoring George Miles, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 35)
  - Economic Club of Pittsburgh, "The Opportunities and Challenges Facing Our Region", 2004 (Box 74, Folder 36)
  - Ellis School, Commencement Address, 2004 (Box 74, Folder 37)
  - Issues of Church and State, c. 2005 (Box 74, Folder 38)
  - Cooper, Bill, Statement by Elsie Hillman on the Death of Bill Cooper, 2006 (Box 74, Folder 39)
  - O'Connor, Bob, Statement by Hillman on the Death of Pittsburgh Mayor Bob O'Connor, 2006 (Box 74, Folder 40)
  - Political Career, Notes, 2007 (Box 74, Folder 41)
  - Pittsburgh Post-Gazette, "GOP must reject reproductive right extremists," by Elsie Hillman, 2009 (Box 74, Folder 42)
  - Pittsburgh Post-Gazette, "A Woman's Job," by Elsie Hillman and Jeanne Caliguiri, 2009 (Box 74, Folder 43)
  - Pittsburgh Post-Gazette, "We must fix the city's long-term financial problems," by Elsie Hillman and David Roderick, 2010 (Box 74, Folder 44)
  - Dantry, Jay, Speech given in honor of Jay Dantry's Bookstand, c. 2011 (Box 74, Folder 45)
  - Chatham University, Speech Honoring Olympia Snowe, 2013 (Box 74, Folder 46)
  - Philadelphia University, Arlen Specter Center for Public Service Dedication, 2014 (Box 74, Folder 47)
  - Writings and Speeches Kept by Hillman, 1986-2007 (Box 74, Folder 48)
- Awards, 1964-2014; VI.
  Series VI contains correspondence, congratulatory notes, newspaper clippings, programs, and speech notes relating to the various awards and honors conferred upon Elsie Hillman for her efforts in both politics and public service. For more information, see Series XIII, Subseries 9: Awards and Honors (Plaques).
  - African American Republican Council of Allegheny County, William P. Young Dinner, Remarks, 1998 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - African American Republican Council of Allegheny Council, Proclamation, 1998 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - American Institute of Architects Pittsburgh Chapter, Gold Medal Award, 2002 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - American Ireland Fund Gala, Guests of Honor, Correspondence and Dinner Program, 2004 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - American Ireland Fund Gala, Guests of Honor, Newspaper Clippings and Magazine Articles, 2004-2005 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Association of Independent Colleges and Universities of Pennsylvania, Robert P. Casey Medal, 2009 (Box 75, Folder 6)